JACK MAHONEY

CHICAGO, IL

Phone Number: 517-574-8060 Email: mahonej79@gmail.com LinkedIn: Jack's Profile GitHub: Jack's GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Jack is a technology professional with a background in cybersecurity, information technology (IT) services, software engineering and electrical engineering. Jack has experience in advising clients with end-user experience, risk analysis, and organization maturity for their respective IT operations as they navigate through securing their network, mitigating risk, and performance improvement projects. His focus remains on improving client experience and developing skills to be a well rounded full stack engineer.

SKILLS

Software: JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, React, Redux, SQL, C, Node.js, Pspice

Expertise: Project Management, Enterprise Architecture, Risk Assessments, Software Licensing (Oracle Licensing SME),

Configuration Management and Change Management, Cyber Recovery Services

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Independent - Chicago IL

Present

- Primarily self-taught developer who has experience in developing in JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, React, HTML, and
 front-end components. Successfully built and deployed <u>jack-mahoney.com</u> website using modern front-end technologies,
 showcasing proficiency in creating visually appealing and user-friendly interfaces
- Demonstrated expertise in version control using Git, ensuring efficient collaboration, code management, and seamless integration of new features and bug fixes for best practices in self managed environments
- Experienced with debugging code and familiar with leveraging AI for increased efficiency

Cybersecurity Risk Management Lead, Infrastructure - Northern Trust - Chicago IL

August 2022 - Present

- Led project for preparation of 2023 Federal cybersecurity assessment. Project consisted of collaborating with stakeholders and conducting gap analysis of current state operations and procedures in alignment to Federal requirements
- Operated the Issue Management Program for identifying, tracking, and closing Infrastructure related Audit and non-Audit issues that pose inherent risk to the cybersecurity of the organization. The process consisted of working with responsible stakeholders to understand the associated risk of the identified issue and develop workstreams to mitigate said risk

Cybersecurity Senior Consultant - Optiv Security - Chicago, IL

July 2021 - August 2022

- Maximized cybersecurity maturity and IT asset value by helping clients understand business sectors for improvement based on NIST and ISO 27001 standards, licensing rules that create compliance risk, unnecessary spending, top cyber threats to the network (internal and external), securing the Software and Development Lifecycle (SDLC), and how the IT Asset Lifecycle fits into each organization's cybersecurity practice
- Identified and provided key technical and strategic initiatives such as network segregation and secure software deployment to improve overall maturity relative to leading Optiv security frameworks, all while reducing risks across the enterprise
- Operated as a full time resource to support financial services CISO in day to day operations. Responsibilities included strategic planning for future state goals, current state risk mitigation, project management of cybersecurity initiatives, and oversight of Identity and Access Management program

Cyber Risk Consultant & Senior Consultant - Deloitte - Chicago, IL

January 2019 - July 2021

- Served multiple Fortune 500 clients, as well as other clients in a diverse array of industries, including the Financial Sector, Semiconductors & Electrical Components, Healthcare, Athletic Apparel, and the Education Sector on how to reduce overall cyber risk by leveraging industry leading practices for Asset Management at the foundational level
- Assessed data feeds and outputs to produce endpoint completeness summary to determine size of client's global endpoint footprint
- Assisted in implementation of ServiceNow Software Asset Management Professional (SAM Pro) within client's existing ServiceNow CMDB; various activities occurred including data validation, data normalization, and tool configuration

EDUCATION

Michigan State University | Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering